<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation of Alumni Data Analytics Project for Staff</title><link>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/</link><description>Recent content on Documentation of Alumni Data Analytics Project for Staff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collect Data</title><link>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/collect-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/collect-data/</guid><description>Collect Data from LinkedIn # First Search # We will first collect alumni information from LinkedIn and copy from their public profile.
Second Search # If the alumni information doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist on LinkedIn, we will move to Google, Facebook, University Faculty Profile, etc to see if there is one. If the alumnus is not able to find after the two searches, they will be marked &amp;quot;Not Found&amp;quot; for further searches.</description></item><item><title>Clean Data</title><link>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/clean-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/clean-data/</guid><description>Clean Data for Faster and Easier Readability and Visualization # Raw Data # The raw data is pretty messy. We have lots of columns that are not useful for this particular project, like Preferred Email, Address, Current Company etc, so we extract only those columns that are essential for later visualization. Useful columns including:
First Name Last Name Gender Class Year Majors All Past Job Titles Years of Service for All Jobs Since the original data is in a Google Sheet, we need to download it as .</description></item><item><title>Visualize Data</title><link>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/visualize-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/doc-ds-staff/docs/doc/process/visualize-data/</guid><description>Visualize Data # Ways of Visualizing # We are currently investigating in which tool is the best for data visualization. Possible choices are Tableau and Power BI.</description></item></channel></rss>